# JOSH FINNIE

□ 860-716-5996 | ☑ josh@jfin.us | ② www.joshfinnie.com | In joshfinnie

#### INTRODUCTION

I am a self-taught, highly-skilled software engineer with over 10 years of expertise in various programming languages. My primary focus is on constructing large-scale and intricate APIs, creating interactive websites, and enhancing internal engineering teams through building tools and creating processes.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### People Data Labs Senior Software Engineer

May 2023 - Present

- · Developing best practices around building API infrastructure using Flask and AWS Lambda.
- · Architecting improvements in how to deliver data to customers.
- · Developed and maintain the PeopleDataLabs Rust SDK.

Technologies: Python (Flask, Django, AWS Lambda), Pulumi, Docker, Rust, AWS RDS (Aurora PostgreSQL), AWS ElastiCache (Redis)

## IndigoAg Staff Software Engineer

May 2022 - March 2023

- · Developed the next generation Carbon Sequestration application API using Flask.
- · Architected the restructuring of the main Backend-for-Frontend application.
- · Developed the adoption of a external partner integration. Lead the process from initial architecture to finial development increasing adoption of the carbon sequestration application.
- · Mentored junior developers and build best-practices throughout the engineering department.
- · Worked with external partners to implement real-time data communication.
- · Wrote technical documentation to improve best-practices for company-wide database backfill proceedure.

Technologies: Python (Flask, FastAPI), PostgreSQL, Javascript (React), Docker, Architecture, Mentorship

## **PBS** Senior Software Engineer

September 2019 - May 2022

- · Modernized legacy Django applications by adding a test suite, upgrading packages, and updating deployment infrastructure to enhance readability and security.
- · Lead development in new GraphQL endpoint for content distribution taking into account different team needs.
- · Developed a deployment infrastructure framework for PBS Engineering to unify how micro-services get deployed to Amazon AWS; written in Go.
- · Was a go-to generalist who helps brain storm and fix cross-team architecture problems along with helping optimizing my team's overall workflow.
- $\cdot$  Developed cross-application best practices for code quality and testing infrastructure.
- · Was a thought leader for experimental changes through out the engineering team at PBS and share learnings through tech talks and presentations.
- · Ran weekly coding practices to better improve PBS Engineering's understanding of complex code issues.

Technologies: Python (Django, Graphene), Javascript (React), Go, CSS (Sass), PostgreSQL, Docker, GraphQL, AWS ECS (EC2, Fargate), AWS ECR

## Skyword (Merged with Trackmaven) Senior Software Engineer

October 2018 - August 2019

- · Lead effort to unify users between the TrackMaven platform and the Skyword platform; creating a unified login micro-service in Django which synced the two platform's authentication.
- · Designed the implementation of best practices for continuous security upgrades for repositories using Snyk, Dependabot and Github Security Hub.

Technologies: Python (Django), PostgreSQL, Redis, Docker, Kubernetes, Github

- · Worked as the lead architect on the migration of our base Django application to Python 3 while also upgrading all application dependencies.
- · Planned and architected of our Kubernetes infrastructure introducing better best-practices in deployment through Terraform.
- · Part the senior engineering team in charge of on-call triage of problems and after-hour deployments of our multiple services.
- · Provided direct technical support to Software Maven team members and collaborative technical support to other departments within TrackMaven.

Technologies: Python (Django), Javascript (React, Node.js), PostgreSQL, Redis, Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform

#### TrackMaven Software Engineer

March 2014 - March 2016

- · Developed testing protocols and best practices to support a successful transition of the live web application from CoffeeScript to modern JavaScript.
- · Established and led a Quality and Infrastructure engineering team that focuses on promoting sound application infrastructure through ensuring high quality code and developing best practices across the engineering department. *Technologies*: Python (Django), Javascript (AngularJS, CoffeeScript), PostgreSQL, Redis, Docker

## Koansys, LLC. Application Developer

February 2012 - March 2014

- · Developed and deployed the Interactive Satellite Tracker (iSat), an application written in JavaScript that calculates satellite positioning in real-time based off of open-source data for Science@NASA,
- · Actively maintained iSat and created application enhancements to meet the needs of Science@NASA.
- · Designed and built cloud infrastructure and automated scripts using Ansible to migrate Science@NASA's Content Management System to Amazon Web Services and from Django to Drupal.

Technologies: Python (Django, Flask), Javascript, Drupal, Amazon Web Services (EC2, S3, Route53, Cloudfront, API Gateway)

#### HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### wasm-frontmatter

https://www.npmjs.com/package/wasm-frontmatter

A clone of grey-matter written in Rust. The rust code is used to generate Wasm code and is then released to NPM. My tests have found that Wasm-Frontmatter is three times faster than the javascript equivalent.

## PushFile

https://www.npmjs.com/package/pushfile

A project written in Node.js which allows you to push a file to Amazon Web Services S3 and gives you an URL in return. This is written using the latest javascript syntax and uses Babel to compile into ES5 to work as a command line application.

More open-source projects at https://www.github.com/joshfinnie/

#### TALKS & PRESENTATIONS

- · Introduction to Python Poetry IndigoAg Internal Tech Talk, February 1st, 2023
- · Introduction to Asynchronous Python IndigoAg Internal Tech Talk, December 8th, 2022
- · gRPC Walkthrough and Programming Showcase PBS Internal Tech Talk, June 23rd, 2021
- · Building Wasm-Frontmatter RustDC, March 16, 2021
- $\cdot$  Intro to Rust and Wasm for Javascript Developers DC JS, December 9, 2020

All talks and presentations at https://www.joshfinnie.com/talks/

# **EDUCATION**

#### Central Connecticut State University

Classes towards a M.S. in Geography (GIS Track).

#### University of Connecticut

B.A. in Economics. (Certificate in Quantitative Economics & Minor in Mathematics).